# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everyone.
# 今天天气稍微好一点了 我就给自己放一天假
It's a nice day today. I decided to take a day off
# 带我女儿来这个
and take my daughter to this...
# 这儿叫啥子场呢
What do we call this place?
# 不晓得 果园嘛
Not sure. A fruit farm?
# （我们来）到果园这边来摘一点蓝莓呀 看看葡萄西红柿这些
(We) came to pick some blueberries, grapes and tomatoes.
# 对吧宝贝
Right, darling?
# 嗯
Um
# 你看 要不摘一个这个没熟的葡萄尝一下
Look. Do you want to try an unripened grape?
# 不能摘 还没熟吧
Don't pick. It's not ripe yet.
# 摘一颗没事 来尝一下吧
One won't hurt. Let's have a taste.
# 酸的是不是
Sour isn't it?
# 诶 你别吐呀
Eh, don't spit on the ground.
# 爸爸也可以吃呀
I can eat it.
# 走吧
Let's go.
# 走 我们去里面
Let's go inside.
# 好吃
Tastes good.
# 甜吗
Is it sweet?
# 等下摘一点回去
We can take some home.
# 睡着了你看
Well someone has fallen asleep.
# 爸爸 这下面有几个蓝莓
Daddy, I can see some blueberries down here.
# 这都是蓝莓呀 来
Those are all blueberries. Come.
# 这都是
They are all blueberries.
# 过来吧
Come here.
# 拿个篮子过去摘嘛
Take a basket and go pick some.
# 挑大的 大的 对
Pick the larger ones. Yes.
# 对了 选大的来摘呀
Good. Choose the large ones.
# 嗯
Um.
# 蓝莓自己掉在了我自己的篮子里面了
Blueberries they fall into my (own) basket.
# 嗯
Um.
# 我也想吃
I want to eat too.
# 我摘一个给你
Let me pick one for you.
# 多摘点我也想吃哦
Go pick some more for mommy.
# 好
Um.
# 给妈妈也摘一点啊
Have some for mommy, OK?
# 嗯
Um.
# 对
Good.
# 哇 你不要弄到地上了 宝贝
Whoa, don't let it fall on the ground, sweetie.
# 接着 我给你拿 我给你接着
Use a basket. Let me hold the basket.
# 摘吧 这里
Go on. Here are some more.
# 诶呀 你好暴力啊
Whoa, you are savage.
# 沺沺你好暴力啊
Tian Tian you are savage.
# 这个蓝莓老板说一定要摘
The owner says,
# 诶
Eh.
# 摘下那颗吧
Can we pick that one?
# 等一下啊
Just a second.
# 这个蓝莓老板说一定要摘大的要摘黑的
The owner says the large and black ones are the best.
# 要不然不甜
They are the sweet ones.
# 要摘黑色的 越黑的越好
Pick the black ones.
# 嗯 比较甜
Um. Very sweet.
# 爸爸 这个好大呀
Daddy, this one is huge.
# 这个就像葡萄一样
They look like grapes.
# 大家可以看一下这个一串一串的像葡萄一样
You can see they grow like grapes in bunches.
# 我以前没有见过蓝莓树
I've never seem blueberry bushes before.
# 今天现场摘一下
Today we experience picking blueberries live.
# 这个蓝莓我们看一下上面有一层灰
See, the blueberries are coated with a layer of powder.
# 老板说是果粉 这个营养价值特别好
The owner says it's called bloom and very nutritious.
# 摘这种大颗的
Pick those large ones.
# 这一串好多哦
This is a large bunch.
# 这个像葡萄一样你看这个
They just look like grapes.
# 但是不黑的、有颜色的、青的都不摘
We leave those colored and green ones.
# 老婆摘黑色的啊
Honey, pick those black ones.
# 不黑的不甜而且也还没熟
The non-black ones aren't sweet.
# 爸爸 我摘得更多
Daddy, I picked a lot.
# 你摘了多少了
How many do you have?
# 这么多呀
This many!
# 像这种你们过来看
Come and have a look.
# 看看看
Look, look!
# 上面那个
That one.
# 啊 这种很甜
Aye, this kind is sweet.
# 哇 这一串特别多
Wow, look at this bunch of blueberries.
# 这个熟的稍微动一下就掉下来了
Ripe and ready to be plucked.
# 妈妈过来 这儿很大的呢
Mommy, come! I have very large ones here.
# 好的 你摘吧
Good. Go pick them.
# 摘多少
How many do you have?
# 我摘了这么一点
Only this many.
# 太多了 我都不知道怎么下手了
There are so many of them. I don't know what to pick.
# 你看嘛
See?
# 沺沺你的呢
Tian Tian where are yours?
# 才摘那么一点 还不如我摘得多 你看
Only that few. Not so many as mine. Look.
# 沺沺 快点
Tian Tian, hurry.
# 还在摘啊
Still picking?
# 对
Yes.
# 宝贝出来出来 我看你摘了多少
Come here, darling. Let me see how many you've got.
# 小心小心 过来
Careful. Come.
# 沺沺都比我摘得多
Tian Tian has more than I do.
# 她都要比你多摘一点
Even she has more than you do.
# 还大个一点呢她摘得
And larger.
# 我们应该目前摘了一斤多吧
We should have about 1 Jin (500g).
# 有没得一斤哦
We have that much?
# 有一哈有一斤
Yes. Around that.
# 这是你的 拿好啊
This is yours. Take it.
# 嗯 沺沺你摘了一个酸的
Um. Tian Tian you've picked a sour one.
# 走吧 我们去看一下其它的
Let's go explore other places.
# 你吃一下这个 沺沺
Try this, Tian Tian.
# 甜吗
Is it sweet?
# 干嘛 酸的是不是
What? Sour, right?
# 酸的你别吐啊 浪费了
Don't spit on the ground. It's a waste.
# 走
Let's go.
# 走嘛
Um.
# 走吧走吧
Let's go.
# 沺沺 沺沺
Tian Tian. Tian Tian.
# 现在让我老婆来摘一下 我来抱一下孩子
I want to relieve my wife from cradling our son and let her have some fun.
# 他睡着了
He's asleep.
# 刚才一直在那里笑 笑着笑着就睡着了
He was smiling all the time before he fell asleep.
# 你们摘呀 我抱着弟弟看你们摘
You guys pick while I and little brother watch.
# 好
OK.
# 沺沺摘大一点的
Tian Tian, go for the big ones.
# 红的 你看
Red, see?
# 好不好玩
Isn't this fun?
# 好玩
Yes.
# 等下回去煎鸡蛋给你吃好不好
You want some fried eggs when we get home?
# 鸡蛋
Eggs?
# 嗯
Um.
# 好
Sure.
# 就煎鸡蛋吃
Just fried eggs.
# 这个更甜
These ones are sweeter.
# 哪个
Which ones?
# 我来摘嘛
Let me pick.
# 我来给它摘了
Let me pick them.
# 这是不
These ones?
# 哇 好透明哦
Wow, it looks translucent.
# 沺沺 你也摘呀
Tian Tian, pick some more.
# 来嘛 我擦一下给你吃
Come, I wiped it.
# 甜不甜
Sweet?
# 嗯
Um.
# 我们这里以前没有这种的
This kind of tomatoes must be newly planted.
# 那干嘛呢
What do you mean?
# 这个应该是后面培育出来的
It is bred recently.
# 培育 我看到有那种子卖啊
It can't be. I saw people sell seeds before.
# 之前我买了很多给我妈妈种
I even bought some for my mom to plant.
# 我们也买点回去种呗
We can also plant some.
# 可以
Sure.
# 你摘了一篮子啊
You have a basket full?
# 对
Yes.
# 妈妈可以给我一点小的吗
Mommy, can I get some smaller ones?
# 差不多了 我们去称一下吧
That's quite enough. Let's go weigh how much we got.
# 嗯
Um.
# 走
Let's go.
# 走嘛
Um.
# 看谁摘得多
Look who's got more.
# 叫奶奶一起 沺沺
Call grandma, Tian Tian.
# 边走边吃啊
Can't stop eating even when walking?
# 好吃吗
How is it?
# 好吃
Good.
# 下次我们又来摘嘛
We can come again if you want.
# 好
OK.
# 今天小孩子已经满了四个月
Our son is four month old today.
# 带他们出来玩一下
I want to bring them out and have some fun.
# 不出来我都不知道原来我们富顺还有这种好地方
We'd never know there's such fun place here at Fu Shun if we stayed at home.
# 好啦
Ok.
# 以后要是你们有时间的话都多带孩子家人出来玩一下
Bring your family out if you have time.
# 因为一辈子不可能就只有工作嘛
Because life isn't all about work.
# 好甜呀 好甜呀 妈妈
Sweet. It's sweet, mommy!
# 过几天又可以摘了 葡萄
Those grapes are to be picked soon.
# 妈妈 好甜呀
Mommy, it's sweet!
# 还要吃吗
You want more?
# 还要
More!